{
  "subject": "National Values and Security Education",
  "year": 2024,
  "quiz": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Cultural diversity means ______ in beliefs.",
      "options": {
        "A": "distractions",
        "B": "differences",
        "C": "similarities",
        "D": "stability",
        "E": "unity"
      },
      "correct": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "The annual fishing festival in Northern Nigeria holds in ______.",
      "options": {
        "A": "Argungu",
        "B": "Birnin Kebbi",
        "C": "Kaduna",
        "D": "Kano",
        "E": "Sokoto"
      },
      "correct": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "A sudden event that happens unexpectedly causing injury and damage is a/an ______.",
      "options": {
        "A": "accident",
        "B": "emergency",
        "C": "hardship",
        "D": "misfortune",
        "E": "shock"
      },
      "correct": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "The injury of the skin caused by boiled water is called ______.",
      "options": {
        "A": "burn",
        "B": "bite",
        "C": "bruise",
        "D": "cut",
        "E": "scald"
      },
      "correct": "E"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "The total way of life of a group of people is ______.",
      "options": {
        "A": "association",
        "B": "culture",
        "C": "norm",
        "D": "socialization",
        "E": "values"
      },
      "correct": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "An example of loyal service to the nation is ______.",
      "options": {
        "A": "dependence on government",
        "B": "disregard to authorities",
        "C": "disregard to national symbols",
        "D": "evading taxes",
        "E": "paying taxes promptly"
      },
      "correct": "E"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "In Nigeria, ethnic crises can be reduced through ______.",
      "options": {
        "A": "inequality",
        "B": "nepotism",
        "C": "sectionalism",
        "D": "tolerance",
        "E": "tribalism"
      },
      "correct": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Which of the following is a traditional symbol?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Coat of arm",
        "B": "Constitution",
        "C": "Currency",
        "D": "Flag",
        "E": "Tribal mark"
      },
      "correct": "E"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "The aspect of society that deals with faith and belief is ______.",
      "options": {
        "A": "culture",
        "B": "economy",
        "C": "politics",
        "D": "religion",
        "E": "socialization"
      },
      "correct": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "Which of the following is considered healthy for consumption?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Expired food",
        "B": "Illicit drug",
        "C": "Infested food",
        "D": "Natural fruit",
        "E": "Rotten food"
      },
      "correct": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "For a nation to be great, ______ must be discouraged.",
      "options": {
        "A": "accountability",
        "B": "corruption",
        "C": "hard work",
        "D": "honesty",
        "E": "tolerance"
      },
      "correct": "B"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "Civic education helps pupils to ______.",
      "options": {
        "A": "acquire wealth",
        "B": "become bad leaders",
        "C": "become patriotic citizens",
        "D": "disobey rules and regulations",
        "E": "embezzle government funds"
      },
      "correct": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "Which of the following is considered as a positive value?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Disobedience",
        "B": "Fighting",
        "C": "Honesty",
        "D": "Kidnapping",
        "E": "Killing"
      },
      "correct": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "The following are characteristics of a nation except common ______.",
      "options": {
        "A": "currency",
        "B": "economy",
        "C": "history",
        "D": "religion",
        "E": "territory"
      },
      "correct": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "Which of the following can lead to insecurity in our homes?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Closing our windows",
        "B": "Keeping our keys safe",
        "C": "Leaving our doors open",
        "D": "Turning on the lights",
        "E": "Using guard dogs"
      },
      "correct": "C"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "Which of the following is not an example of a crime prevention measure?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Barking dogs",
        "B": "Burglary proofs",
        "C": "Security cameras",
        "D": "Streetlights",
        "E": "Unprotected windows"
      },
      "correct": "E"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "Reporting any suspicious person to law enforcement agents is a sign of ______ security.",
      "options": {
        "A": "consciousness",
        "B": "request",
        "C": "risk",
        "D": "sabotage",
        "E": "threat"
      },
      "correct": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "Taking drugs without a doctor's prescription is drug ______.",
      "options": {
        "A": "abuse",
        "B": "addiction",
        "C": "pushing",
        "D": "production",
        "E": "trafficking"
      },
      "correct": "A"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "A citizen of Nigeria that resides in another country is called a/an ______.",
      "options": {
        "A": "ambassador",
        "B": "businessman",
        "C": "diplomat",
        "D": "foreigner",
        "E": "high commissioner"
      },
      "correct": "D"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "Which of the following sources of water is man-made?",
      "options": {
        "A": "Ocean",
        "B": "Rain",
        "C": "River",
        "D": "Stream",
        "E": "Well"
      },
      "correct": "E"
    }
  ]
}
